dmexco-imgdb.de 2017-06-06

# Security and data protection | Koelnmesse

Wherever this website enables the user to enter personal or business details (email addresses, names, postal addresses), the user reveals such information on an expressly voluntary basis. All of the services provided may also be used and paid for without entering such data or by entering anonymous data or a pseudonym, provided this is technically possible and reasonable.

### Data protection declaration for the use of Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager

This website uses Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager, Web analysis services from Google Inc. (“Google”). Both tools employ “cookies”, which are text files that are stored on your computer and make it possible to analyze how you are using the website. The information created by the cookie concerning your use of this website is normally transferred to a Google server in the U.S. and stored there. The activation of IP anonymization on this website with the code "anonymizeIp" means that your IP address is, however, shortened by Google within the member states of the European Union or in other states that are signatories of the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

Only in exceptional cases is the complete IP address transferred to a Google server in the U.S. and shortened there. Google uses this information at the request of, and on behalf of, the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, to create reports on the website activities, and to provide the website’s operator with additional services connected with the use of the website and the Internet. 

You can prevent the storage of the cookies by carrying out a corresponding setting in your browser software; however, we expressly inform you that in this case you may not be able to use the full scope of all of the features of this website. In addition, you can disable the cookie’s sending of the data it has created concerning your use of this website (including your IP address) to Google and the processing of this data by Google if you download and install the browser plugin that is available under the following link:  [ http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de ](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de)

You can refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website:  
Disable Google Analytics 

Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at  

### Social plugins from Facebook, Twitter, Google+, LinkedIn and Xing

We offer you on our website the possibility to use so-called social plugins from the following companies:

  * „Share“-Button from Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA;
  * „Tweet“-Button from Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA;
  * „+1“-Button from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA;
  * „Recommended-Button“ von LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA;
  * „Share-Button“ from XING AG, Gänsemarkt 43, 20354 Hamburg, Germany.

To protect the privacy of your data, we implement this with the solution “Shariff”. By doing this, the plugins are displayed on our website merely as graphics (images) that contain a link to the website of the plugin provider. By clicking on the graphic you will be forwarded to the services of the provider. Only then will your data be sent to the providers. As long as you do not click on the plugin graphic, there will be no transmission of data between you and the so-called social networks.

More information about the collection and usage of your data in social networks can be found in the terms and conditions of the individual service providers. More information about the Shariff solution can be found  [ here ](https://www.heise.de/ct/artikel/Shariff-Social-Media-Buttons-mit-Datenschutz-2467514.html) .

### EXPANDED DATA PROTECTION REGULATIONS

### Our data protection policy

To ensure that we can successfully provide expert services, we strive to collect as much information as possible on our customers and business partners. At the same time, the protection of personal data is something we take very seriously. Our customers, business partners and employees should all be aware of Koelnmesse’s policy with regard to personal data, and we give everyone the opportunity to influence how their data is collected, processed and used.

### Scope of the Data Protection Regulations

These Data Protection Regulations are valid for all personal data collected, processed or used by Koelnmesse or its subsidiaries. This includes information that we received as a result of your participation in a trade fair or other event and your business correspondence with our company as well as data that was passed on to us by third parties to use for international trade fair purposes.

Also included is data contained in your registration documents, information received from your visits to our websites (which is used for purposes of technical administration) and data obtained as a result of a security check to determine if you are authorized to access any protected Internet pages.

### Why should you provide Koelnmesse with personal information?

By providing us with your personal details, we can, in return, offer you several benefits. Specifically, it becomes easier and more convenient for you to

  * plan your visit to a trade fair, because we can provide you with specific information in the run-up to the event
  * register as a visitor for certain events, so that you can receive all the benefits to which you are entitled by purchasing a ticket online
  * receive personal messages and special offers from us or our exhibitors
  * smoothly plan and carry out your trade fair participation while benefiting from the Koelnmesse Group’s extensive range of services
  * save time so that you can devote yourself to topics that really interest you

By providing us with your data, you also enable us to conduct market research so that we can provide better services and customer care, and further optimize our offerings.

You can provide us with your personal details in a variety of ways, e.g. by creating an account for our e-shop, by faxing us a visitor or exhibitor registration form, by entering a competition, by registering in person at the exhibition centre or by taking part in a survey.

### What kind of personal data do we collect?

Whenever you visit one of our websites, our servers generally store not only the technical parameters needed for transferring web page data, but also the following information:

  * Date, time and length of your visit to one of our web pages
  * The IP number that has been assigned to you by your Internet provider
  * The web page you are currently visiting
  * The tool (i.e. web browser, operating system) you have used to access the site
  * The carried out action on our website
  * The terms you use in the search engines and for the site search and the search result
  * Whether a site was successfully accessed or not
  * What information was called up (incl. downloads)
  * From which server and which website you accessed the site

### Cookies and website logs

Some of our web pages transmit a cookie (a small text file) to your computer, which allows us to recognize your computer the next time you visit our website. If you do not want to receive any cookies, select your Internet browser’s “Help” function to find out how to either deactivate all cookies or receive a warning before a cookie can be saved. If you would like to learn more about cookies, visit:  [ www.cookiecentral.com ](http://www.cookiecentral.com/)

Whenever you visit our website to browse, read articles or download information, we collect and save data related to your visit: e.g. a clearly defined ID; the name of the host and the domain from which you have accessed the Internet, your computer’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, the date and time at which you accessed the website, and the URL of the website from which you have directly accessed our website. We use this information to monitor visits to our websites and to recognize repeat visitors. This information helps us make our websites even more useful. However, we delete this information again after a certain amount of time has elapsed.

Additional data is saved only if it is needed to process a visit to a trade fair or other event staged at Koelnmesse or if you voluntarily provide us with such information.

However, Koelnmesse may from time to time also receive your personal data from third parties. This can happen, for example, when personal information is forwarded by associations, exhibitors, foreign representatives, chambers of commerce and industry, or commercial address brokers. If you do not want us to use personal data that you have not directly sent us, please contact the address in the legal notice and notify us of this fact.

If you send us any emails, we collect, process and use your personal data to help us provide our services and conduct any necessary correspondence. This is also the case when you send us contact forms, letters or faxes. You can of course stipulate at any time that your details should not be used for advertising purposes. You are regularly made aware of this right in all of our informational and advertising letters.

We have taken every technical and organizational step required to ensure that all of the data that is collected, processed or used is protected against loss, deletion, tampering, forgery, unauthorized access or unauthorized forwarding.

In addition, our employees are obliged to keep data confidential. They regularly receive training in data protection and data security.

 **Which information do we forward?**

Koelnmesse forwards your personal data to third parties if this is necessary to process your orders, organize your trade fair participation or invoice services.

However, our aims are more far-reaching. We wish to get to know you and bring you into contact with our partners and interesting exhibitors. What’s more, we want to be able to give you even more support for your next trade fair participation.

However, it is your choice if you wish to take advantage of additional services and provide us with data that we can forward to third parties.

For visitors to events organized by Koelnmesse, we forward trade visitor data to exhibitors, associations or other third parties only under the following conditions:

  * The trade visitor has not objected or, if necessary, has given permission to have his/her data forwarded to exhibitors, associations or third-party companies
  * Before forwarding data to exhibitors, associations or third-party companies based abroad, we always check to see if the data protection standards in the recipient’s home country are comparable to those in Germany. If not, the recipient is obliged to contractually assure Koelnmesse that corresponding data protection standards will be met

or

  * Koelnmesse sells a trade fair event to another company. As a result of such a sale, personal data that is directly related to the event may be forwarded to the buyer.  
Koelnmesse does not sell or otherwise transfer your personal data to third parties for any other reason.  
Our foreign representatives and our service partners in Germany and abroad are contractually obliged to fully comply with the pertinent data protection and data security regulations and guidelines. Koelnmesse checks to see that this obligation is met.

### The protection of your data

We take our responsibility for protecting the information that has been entrusted to us very seriously. Koelnmesse uses a wide range of data security techniques, including secure servers, firewalls and encryption of financial data.

Koelnmesse websites can include forums, notice boards and newsgroups as well as chat rooms. Please bear in mind that personal data which you disclose at these sites is accessible to other users. You should therefore carefully consider the potential consequences before disclosing such information.

### Your rights

If you have given us personal data, we will provide you with appropriate access to the information that we have stored about you so that you can change or delete it. You can do so by writing to the address in the legal notice below and requesting a copy of your profile.

### Contact

 **Our contact details**

You can find our address in the ‘legal notice’ in the lowerleft margin of this page.  
Please let us know if you should have any concerns regarding the way we treat your personal data. We will immediately look into the matter.

##  The public procedural directory 

As stipulated by Par. 4g of the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG), data protection officers must provide the following information in accordance with Par. 4e of the BDSG:

1\. Name of the responsible organizations | 2\. Management | 3\. Address of the responsible organizations  
---|---|---  
Koelnmesse GmbH  | Gerald Böse (Chief Executive Officer)  
Katharina C. Hamma  
Herbert Marner  
Authorized head of Data Processing:  
Achim Stolzki | Messeplatz 1, 50679 Köln, Germany  
Koelnmesse Ausstellungen GmbH | Sandra Orth  
Authorized head of Data Processing:  
Achim Stolzki | Messeplatz 1, 50679 Köln, Germany  
  
### 4\. The purpose of collecting, processing and using data

The company’s mission is to promote business by organizing trade fairs and exhibitions in Germany and abroad, by organizing and staging congresses and conferences, and by engaging in activities and offering services related to the trade fair, exhibition, congress and conference business. To fulfill its mission, the company maintains trade fair and exhibition facilities as well as conference rooms and convention halls. It uses these facilities for its events or rents them out for an appropriate fee. The company is also entitled to use its grounds for events of an athletic, cultural or other nature or to rent out its facilities for this purpose. Data is collected, processed and used to fulfill the above-mentioned mission.

The temporary storage of your IP adress has the purpose of filtering out the accesses of the website operator and its service providers to improve the range of services and the overall experience of the service. In case of serious violations of our terms of use and of unlawful access or attempted access to our servers, we reserve the right to use individual data records to track personal information.

### 5\. Description of the groups affected and the relevant data and data categories

Visitor data, exhibitor data, other business partner data, employee data insofar it is needed to fulfill the purpose listed in item 4.

### 6\. Recipients or categories of recipients to whom the data can be transmitted

Public authorities if higher-priority legal regulations require it; external contractors in accordance with Par. 11 BDSG; representatives in Germany and abroad; subsidiaries; service partners; exhibitors; associations; external organizations and internal departments in order to fulfill the purposes listed in item 4.

### 7\. Standard periods until the data is deleted

The law contains a number of regulations concerning the obligation to store data and the periods for storing such data. At the end of these periods, the affected data is routinely deleted. Data that is not deleted at this time is deleted as soon as the purposes listed in item 4 no longer apply.

### 8\. Data transmission to non-EEA countries (“third countries”)

The personal data of German citizens or citizens of other EU countries is forwarded to third countries that do not offer a sufficiently high level of data protection only if the recipient of the data has accepted the stipulations of the EU-standard contract.

(Status: May 2017)
